

PROFILE

As a Content Developer in the IT sector, I was responsible for researching, creating, and optimizing content that educates, informs, and engages our target audience.

My primary focus will be on producing high-quality content related to technology, software products, IT services, and industry trends. This job requires a unique blend of technical knowledge, creativity, and communication skills to communicate complex IT concepts to a diverse audience effectively.

CONTACT

PHONE:

+91-8607913392

BLOG:

https://medium.com/@prateekgupta2

EMAIL:

prateekgupta2863@gmail.com

SOFT SKILLS

Communication Creativity Problem-Solving Adaptability Time Management Critical Thinking

PRATEEK GAUTAM GUPTA

SR. Associate Content Operation

EDUCATION

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore, Tamil Nadu

July 2018 - June 2022

Bachelor of Technology, Stream - Information Technology, CGPA - 8.0

D.A.V Public School, Ambala Cantt, Haryana

- Higher Secondary Education, April 2017 - March 2018

Stream - PCM, Aggregate - 84.6%

- Secondary Education, April 2015 - March 2016, Grade - 9.8

WORK EXPERIENCE

VCriate - Sr. Associate Content Operation Apr 2023 - Mar 2024

Led and directed a team of 12 individuals within my purview, orchestrating the conception of IT content spanning diverse technologies, platforms, and skills.

VCriate - Content Developer

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023

It was aimed at producing high-quality content related to technology, software products, IT services, and industry trends.

VCriate - Backend Developer

May 2023 - Oct 2023

Collaborating with senior developers to design and implement scalable and efficient backend solutions. Tasked with writing clean, maintainable code in languages such as Java, or Node.js.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Content Development
Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
Web Content Writing
Content Creation & Strategy
Analytical Skills
Technical Documentation, Information & Report

CERTIFICATION

- Software Engineering Virtual Experience at JPMorgan CHASE & Co.
- Data Analytics Virtual Experience Program at Quantium
- Data@ANZ Program at ANZ.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript – Advanced Level MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, Node.JS – Intermediate Level C++, Python, PHP – Intermediate Level Java – Advance Level

HOBBIES

Singing Swimming Sketching & Painting Reading books

LANGUAGES

Engish Hindi Punjabi Spanish

- Artificial Intelligence at Pantech e-Learning
- Algorithmic Toolbox, University of California San Diego
- Introduction to HTML5, University of Michigan
- Object-oriented programming in Java, University of California San Diego
- Full Stack Java, at Udemy

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Research and understand the latest trends, technologies, and developments in the IT industry.
- Develop content that effectively communicates technical concepts in a clear and accessible manner for diverse audiences.
- Collaborate with subject matter experts, product managers, and sales teams to gather information and insights for content creation.
- Optimize content for SEO (Search Engine Optimization) to increase visibility and drive organic traffic to our digital platforms.
- Create engaging and informative content for various channels including websites, blogs, whitepapers, case studies, social media, email campaigns, and more.
- Ensure all content is accurate, up-to-date, and aligned with brand guidelines and messaging.
- Edit and proofread content to ensure quality, consistency, and adherence to style guidelines.
- Stay updated with industry best practices and content marketing trends to improve content strategies continuously.

PROJECTS

- Developed content for multiple skills like Oracle Administration, Talend, Kinaxis, SAP Customer Relationship Management (CRM): WEB UI Technical, S/4HANA Enterprise Management -Human Capital Management, and many more. Target audience – fresher level to 8 years of experienced candidates.
- Develop interview content for the Google Certified Courses like GCP DevOps, Action driven business plan, and Google Analytics.
- Created test interview scenarios and codes for Jenkins, EMC –
 Documentum/Captiva, Progress OpenEdge, Snaplogics,
 Ngnix, and OpenStack-enabled NFV/SDN for test candidates
 with an experience range of 4 to 6 years
- Develop interview content for the **Microsoft Certified Azure Data Engineer Associate Certification**.
- Created and supervised content for bachelor's and 12th standard content for PCM and advanced-level mathematics.

PATENT

 Utility Patent titled "SYSTEM AND DEVICE FOR DETECTION OF AIR POLLUTION" has been filed at the Indian Patent Office on 03 May 2022 – 202211025775.